strongertoms@gmail.com < 7203045826 Louisville, KY in www.linkedin.com/in/trstrong ThomasStrong

Objective

As a proven problem-solver my years of experience processing documents for publication, building spreadsheet calculators, and navigating software for scientific instruments (Scanning Electron Microscope, X-Ray Diffraction, SelFrag Lab, etc.), has shown me that coding is the ultimate tool of creation. I look forward to enriching and applying my development skills while devising solutions and creating environments and complex structures.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, Typescript, YAML, C++ Technologies: ReactJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Postman, Webpack, Node.js

Other: Git, Visual Basic, ArcGIS, Jade 9, Minitab, **NSS Spectral Imaging**

Education

Code Louisville Web Development II 2022 Web Development I 2022

Metropolitan State University of Denver B.S. Applied Geology (Cum

Laude)

> Projects

FindMeABeer

June 2022 to July 2022

Single Page App - https://thomasstrong.github.io/beer-finder/

- · Built via React boilerplate and State Hook.
- fetch() method for API request, parse in JSON.
- Full user search form with multiple factors.

Monolith Lapidary

Feb. 2022 to Mar. 2022

Product Landing Site - https://thomasstrong.github.io/Monolith Lapidary/

- Employed ES6 solely to generate a product landing page.
- Utilized Flexbox and Grid to create a responsive site.
- · Constructed via mobile-first programming.

CSS Memory Game

Apr. 2022

Game - https://thomasstrong.github.io/CSS Memory Game/

- Employed ES6 and CSS3 to create a fun game of Memory.
- Utilized Grid dynamically via vanilla JavaScript.
- Developed simple, responsive array for user choice.

Employment

The Stave Restaurant & Bar

Frankfort, KY Oct. 2018 to Mar. 2020

Server/Bartender/Supervisor

- Consistently provided outstanding customer service through creative solutions leading to retention of repeat customers.
- Experience and excellent communication facilitated the maintenance of multiple roles as necessary for continued service.

United States Geological Survey (USGS)

Central Mineral and Environmental Resources Science Center, Denver, Colorado

Physical Scientist I

Jan. 2014 to Aug. 2018

- Created and maintained an extensive database (1,000+) of sample throughput that followed the internal life of samples and required collaboration between multiple agents.
- Established pre-analysis checks of samples through X-ray diffraction and X-ray fluorescence.
- Developed and published Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for sample processing, which involved extensive testing of known and unknown methods. https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr20161022
- Constructed SOP for new equipment and provided concurrent development, as with high-voltage pulse power fragmentation (SelFrag Lab) for samples.
- Successfully captured and provided identification of samples via Scanning Electron Microscope and reflected and transmitted-light microscopes.